Inside Llewyn Davis is a drama, music film directed by Joel Coen.
In Greenwich Village in the early 1960s, gifted but volatile folk musician Llewyn
Davis struggles with money, relationships, and his uncertain future.
Llewyn Davis, played by Oscar Isaac.
Jean, played by Carey Mulligan.
Jim, played by Justin Timberlake.
Mitch Gorfein, played by Ethan Phillips.
Lillian Gorfein, played by Robin Bartlett.
Pappi Corsicato, played by Max Casella.
Inside Llewyn Davis () is a 2013 period black comedy drama film written,
directed, produced, and edited by Joel and Ethan Coen.
Set in 1961, the film follows one week in the life of Llewyn Davis, played by Oscar Isaac in his breakthrough
role, a folk singer struggling to achieve musical success while keeping his life in order.
The supporting cast includes Carey Mulligan, John Goodman, Garrett Hedlund, F.
Murray Abraham, Justin Timberlake and Adam Driver.
Though Davis is a fictional character, the story was partly
inspired by folk singer Dave Van Ronk's autobiography.
Most of the folk songs performed in the film are sung in full and recorded live.
T Bone Burnett was the executive music producer.
Principal photography took place in early 2012, primarily in New York City.
The film, an international co-production between companies in France, the United Kingdom and the
United States, was financed by StudioCanal before it received an American distributor.
Inside Llewyn Davis premiered at the 2013 Cannes Film Festival
on May 19, 2013, where it won the Grand Prix.
The film was theatrically released in France on November 6, 2013, and in
the United Kingdom on January 24, 2014, by StudioCanal.
It was given a limited release by CBS Films in the United States on December
6, 2013, before opening in a wide release on January 10, 2014.
The film received critical acclaim and was nominated for two Academy Awards (Best Cinematography and Best Sound Mixing) and three Golden Globe
Awards for Best Motion Picture – Comedy or Musical, Best Actor – Motion Picture Musical or Comedy (Isaac), and Best Original Song.
Inside Llewyn Davis has been held in high critical esteem since its release as one of the greatest films ever made, being
voted the 11th-best film of the 21st century in both a 2016 BBC poll and a 2017 The New York Times list.
The film was ranked 14 on Rolling Stone magazine's list of "50 Best Movies of the 2010s" and 2 on
The Hollywood Reporter's list of the "50 Best Films of the 21st Century (So Far)."
The film explores themes of depression, new york city, guitar, winter, cat.
The tone is dark and emotional.